Let me start just letting you know ahead of time that I've been asked to keep my message
for 15 minutes, which is really hard for me. And I'm a believer that we should continually
learn in whatever we do. And so you're my game kid today. As a governor for myself, I'm
going to try to preach from a manuscript. I've never done it before, but we're going to give
it a shot. And it's the one way to corral myself. I've talked to this five times this morning
and it's between 11 and 15 minutes. So that's good. And number two, I've seen some folks
do a really amazing job preaching with a manuscript. And I thought, why not give a response to
them? So bear with me. You know, there are four words that are most connected with Advent.
Hope, love, joy, peace. Today's words love unfortunately suffers from a maligning culture often focused
on sexual desires relative to love rather than biblical descriptors like patience, kindness, not
seeking its own. Cultural distortions like sappy, country, western songs. Or manipulative testosterone
riddled teenage rucks seeking stuff by asking the saints who love me. Or recognized catchphrases
like love brings. To reduce morality to a personal desire. Biblical love, however, much more than
this. Bob Gaff approaches it in his biblical book, biblical love book titled Love Does.
Well, love does. While love may carry deep affections with it, you know, I often say, God only loves
you, he likes you. He's not sedent you. But the truth will the loving act of Advent, the Incarnation,
his coming
at some feelings of desire
or affection.
I've got more of that
right now.
Maybe I'll stick with his name.
It's just
just a little bit much.
Christ
Incarnation.
Jesus was
perfect.
And we're talking
perfect
perfection.
Jesus was in
perfect community
with the Father
and with the Spirit.
We talk about
koinonia.
Absolute
perfect
koinonia
from which
he chose
voluntarily
to leave
and answer
the first
pool of human
relationships.
You know,
if I think about
Mother Teresa
entering the
city of joy,
Jesus' coming
is like that
on stairways.
Mother Teresa
was an Albanian
nun who
chose to leave
the comforts
of her nunnery
and gave
the city of joy,
which was a place
in Calcutta,
India.
Some of the poorest
of the poor,
the place a little
marginalized,
were forced to live.
The low spot
in the city
where when the sewers
would overflow,
they would flood
that area
during the monsoon
and people would have
to walk
in need
to get deep water
that was infested
with open sewers.
And the small
of three feet
difference between
her nunnery
and death
is this part of
Jesus' heaven
was over there
and he came here.
The challenge
is more about
the death.
St. Francis
of Assisi
in the self-imposed
penance
because he had
offended a letter,
he had
achieved a letter
in something
love-spending,
recognized in his own
demeanor what he
has done,
and forced
opponents upon
himself to train
himself to have
a common meal
with this brother
with advanced
lecithy where his
fingers are now
dripping from his
hands and the
first digit is
almost gone
and together
they had a
common meal
out of one bowl.
And as I think
about that
and that sick
feeling of the
song,
and what
St. Francis
of a recent
chemistry
even with the
leper
is feared
as well,
Jesus started
right over there
and in the
incarnation
he came
here.
Have any of you
like me
ever wondered
how Jesus
escaped the
mental wounding
that often
accompanied
to
the
realities?
Jesus in the
understanding
of his
whole community
was the product
of premarital
sex in a world
where children
were ostracized
along with
their mother.
His formative
years
were spent
before in
constant
and while
you were the
ancient
and a young
child,
his formative
years
were stuck
to develop
inside of you
and the best
he was an
immigrant at worst
through the rest
of the years.
Scripture tells us
that he was
defied.
It says,
quote,
nothing in his
appearance
that we should
goodbye to him.
That's a kind
of word
of song of it.
He was rejected
by his own
community.
All of these
things we've
created or
we've identified,
we've recognized
syndromes that
happen to
us today.
Anyone else
ever wonder
how Jesus
ended up
without the
psychological
syndromes
in the
mysticism
convention?
This morning
I'm going to
talk about
love.
There are
words to
all of them
today.
The Bible
calls us
the two
progressively
radical
manifestations
of love.
The first
is,
love your
neighbor
as you
said.
Matthew 22,
34 through
40,
lays about.
We find
Jesus where
Jewish leaders
are trying
to discredit
him.
The Sadducees
have failed.
The Scriptures
say that they
were silenced
by Jews
and so
the Pharisees
tag teams
into a
wrestling match
of Jesus.
The Pharisees
out the
Pharisees
enemies
under
disgrace
Jesus.
And they
say for
extra
on the
law,
asking.
What's the
greatest
commandment?
And you
know Jesus
is thanks.
Love the
Lord your
God with
all your
heart,
soul,
love you,
strength.
And the
second is
like it.
Love your
neighbor
as you
said.
For all
the law
and the
prophets
come on
these
two
commands.
James,
Jesus'
natural
brother and
leader of
the early
church,
echoed these
words.
He talked
about the
royal love,
that royal
law of love,
found in
Scripture,
love your
neighbor as
yourself.
And then he
conjects it
to which of it.
He puts it
over again,
showing
savorism to
people like
you,
the people you
like,
the people who
can further
your agenda.
This is why
we're here
today,
folks.
Because love
is not a
feeling.
It's not the
fulfillment of
a desire.
Love
wins not
when it
secures
perceived
right or
gets beyond
third base
with its
girlfriend,
but when
it serves
its
community.
I think
our
litigy
today will
be praised.
Thank you,
Donovan,
for leading
hearing
of the
word,
preaching
of the
word.
And number
three,
serving
our
neighbor.
And so
since
litigy is
actually
grounded in
Romans 12
verse 1,
different
translations
render the
exact same
words that
Paul says
in that
verse
intentionally,
one
translation
rendition
is spiritual
worship,
and the
other is
reasonable
service.
In other
words,
in the
words
that
Paul
shows,
the
fear
of
understanding
is
spiritual
worship
and
reasonable
service.
Therefore,
I urge you,
brothers and
sisters,
in view of
God's
mercy,
to offer
your bodies
as a living
and sacrifice
fully and
pleasing to
God.
This is
your
word to
worship
Christ
reasonable
service.
I think
Matt
Redman
hit it
right in
Hard Horse
if it's
more
than
a
son.
By
way,
an argument
of the book
is you keep
his wife
repressed.
Antonin
now is
the
Densky,
who ran
Europe's
largest zoo
like a game
type in the
outskirts of
Warsaw.
Until
during World
War II,
German
Blitzkrieg
used
the
East
West
to
bomb
Warsaw
into
rubble.
Most
of the
animals
that
were
left
at
that
point
were
shipped
back
to
Germany.
The
remaining
ones
became
entertainment
as a
private
hunting
garden
for
SF
officers.
As a
Christian,
he felt
compelled
to care
for
creation,
Antonin
now was
devastated.
But she
said,
it was
not to
dream of
death,
but merely
a week
of sleep.
before God
could use
the wicked
in the
day for
his good
purpose.
And when
her husband
Jan was
appointed by
the Nazis
as
superintendent
of the
clerks,
she opened
a pit
farm on
the
gardens
to
remove
one of
his
occupiers
from
Haiti
Jews.
And while
the Nazis
systematically
killed
thousands
of Polish
Jews
from
starvation
in the
Warsaw
ghetto,
finally
he was
sending
others
to death
to us.
Antonin
smuggled
pork
to
starving
Jews
and
used
a
labyrinth
of
pages
in the
park
ground
to
hide
hundreds
of
Jews
which
he
eventually
smuggled
out
to
safety.
That's
the
under
a tree
along
Jerusalem's
avenue
of the
righteous
among the
nations
when he
yelled
to them
all across
the
hands.
Jesus
says
love
you
neighbor.
Love
you
neighbor.
But in
John
through
Jesus
gives
a more
radical
command
of
life.
Brothers
this one
is not
focused so
much on
neighbor
but on
all
brothers.
Those
who are
in the
household
of
God.
Context.
Judas
has just
blessed
the last
couple
thank
unto
Israel
Jesus
for a
few
gold
things.
Jesus
declares
that the
testicus
of his
crucifixion
quote
now the
son of
man is
glorified.
By the
way I
know that
you know
the
crucifixion
doesn't
typically
parallel to
glory in
my thinking
but it
does in
what's
the
time
of
Jesus.
Now
the
son of
man is
glorified
and God
is glorified
in him.
Next
Jesus
is
as he
said
I'm
going to
do
something
you
don't
want to
do.
You're
going to
watch
me
suffer
and you're
going to
watch me
die for
you.
So it's
a leadership
of a
shepherd
not a
cattle holder.
Tattle
holders drive
others with
their agenda.
Shepherds
lead by
going
first.
They model.
Jesus in
essence
is saying
because I
love you
I am
going to
die and
this kind
of love
it glorifies
father.
But then
Jesus
says
I
hear
the
touch
for
it.
A
new
command
they
give
to
you
love
one
another.
Let me
tell you
what I
mean by
that
Jesus
faith.
As I
have
loved
you
as you're
going to
watch
my love
for you
manifest
in my
willingness
to go to
the cross
on your
behalf
to suffer
as I
have
loved
you
so you
must
love
one
another.
By this
everyone
will know
that you
are my
defender
if you
love
one
another.
Folks
love your
neighbor.
Love your
neighbor
even
love
one
another
beyond
you.
Jesus
says
love
one
another
as I
have
loved
you
and
when
you
do
that
people
will
pay
attention
in
the
future
year
before
it.
April
26,
its
noble
nuclear
power
training
did
U-10
explode
and
releases
tons
of
radiation
Hiroshima.
That
explosion
initiated
a lava
flow
of
radioactive
molten
metal
toward
the
pool
of
cooling
water.
If it
reached
the
pool
it
would
have
set
off
a
more
massive
explosion
not only
leveling
the
entire
plant
but
destroying
peace
of
Europe.
We're
talking
both
rest
and
east
rendering
it
uninhabitable
for
years.
Three
workers.
We don't
know the
names.
Three
workers
volunteered
to
wade
through
knee
deep
radioactive
water
in a
pitch
black
basement
to
open
subtle
sandals
and drain
the
pool.
They
volunteered
knowing
that the
exposure
of a
violent
attempt
would
result
in
certain
slow
agonizing
deaths
over the
next few
months
from
radiation
poisoning.
excruciating
this.
Following
the
underwater
pipes
down
home
the
volunteers
fell
in the
bounds
and
draining
the
pool.
Those
above
heard the
water
forcing
out
of the
basement
and erupted
in spontaneous
story and
to be honest
I have to
believe that
the two
volunteers
felt both
to find
joy
and
devastating
fear.
You know
some of the
denominations
of those
two
heroes
remain
anonymous
because
of a
Soviet
trouble.
You know
I guess
it only
asks the
illustration.
I often
joke that
I'm willing
to pick up
the garbage
but I won't
sell it
for it.
The fear
is love
not for
a grand
blessing.
It's
love for
life.
Today
folks
our
spiritual
worship
is a
reasonable
service
as we
love our
neighbors
against
as we
love
and
friends.
With that
I pray
that the
people
would be
grace
between
limiting
us to
love
our
neighbors
and
ourselves
to
love
one
another
as
Christ
loves
ourselves
to the
glory
of God.
Mike
can you
come and
tell us
how we
can love
our
neighbor?
May the
Holy Spirit
tell us
how we
can love
one another
as
Christ
loves
us.